<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Thinking in Design]]></title>
  <link href="http://hcid.us/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hcid.us/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-26T16:24:11-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://hcid.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chaoyu Yang]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Model Prototype Assignment: Handheld Device]]></title>
    <link href="http://hcid.us/blog/2014/01/25/model-prototype-assignment-handheld-device/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-25T23:47:39-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://hcid.us/blog/2014/01/25/model-prototype-assignment-handheld-device</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Background</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a2/title.jpg" width="300"></p>

<p>The subject for our second assignment in the prototyping studio, is creating a 3D lo-fi prototype of a handheld device with physical and digital control. We have two product to choose from: an immersion blender or a stud finder. The challenge here is to apply OXO brand and its universal design elements to a new product space. Which means the device I design should be accessible and usable for a wide range of users.</p>

<p>Another challenge for me is that I have never use both equipments in my life before. So that I need to do research in the regular workflow of using these devices and study the current market of both products. After a short research, I decided to go with immersion blender because I can’t only find a blender that is accessible, so I can borrow and play with it.</p>

<h2>Design</h2>

<p>The <a href="http://www.oxo.com/">OXO</a> brand is known for applying universal design to deliver well-designed, easy to use tools for cooking and food preparation. I started with thinking about how to make a handheld blender that can work with different size of hands, and what kind of shape can achieve this goal. So I started to do some sketch like this:</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a2/catchup.png" width="140"></p>

<p>Sketching is an effective way to think with paper, but to design a physical object, it’s much better to think with our hands. So I turned to hold different objects such as water bottle, catch-up bottle, or folding umbrella, and try to use it as an immersion blender. And also by wrapping some tinfoil on the outside of those objects, I can change the shape easily and explore more opportunities within a very short period of time.</p>

<p>After some exploring in different shapes and solutions, I chosed three directions to create a physical model.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Model 1</h2>

<p>The first model is in the shape of a drill. It have two button on the shank to operate the blender to accelerate and decelerate. I use foam to create the whole gun body as it’s extremely easy to create customized shape. The “gunpoint” and barrel is made of wire and foam. And I put some clay inside of the gun body to make it heavier so it feels like there is a real motor inside the object.</p>

<p><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a2/model1-sketch.png" width="256"><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a2/model1.jpg" width="256"><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a2/model1.gif" width="288"></p>

<h2>Model 2</h2>

<p>I design this model based on the idea of catch-up bottle. When using a handheld blender, we always need to move the blender up and down. And it’s important to let user hold the device tightly because of the potential danger when the motor is working. I found the shape of a collapsed catch-up bottle feels good for a blender, so I make the handgrip in this shape and but the switches on the position of the thumb.</p>

<p>The whole body was made of clay and wrapped it with tape. The whisk part is made of a wood stick and some foam wrapped with tinfoil.</p>

<p><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a2/model2-sketch.png" width="277"><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a2/model2.jpg" width="277"><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a2/model2.gif" width="246"></p>

<h2>Model 3</h2>

<p>This model also use the catch-up bottle approach. And I made it standable with the button. You may ask why I need a blender to stand on the opposite way. The reason is that after blending some food, the whisk part will get dirty and maybe some juices were sticked to it. If you put the dirty part on the table, both table and the whisk part may become dirty. I granulated the neck part to prevent the juices flow down to the handgrip. For this model, the body is made of clay and the neck part is made of foam.</p>

<p><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a2/model3-sketch.png" width="272"><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a2/model3.jpg" width="272"><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a2/model3.gif" width="256"></p>

<h2>Test &amp; Analysis</h2>

<p>Many problems are revealed during the test. For the model 1, I found it’s much harder to operate it for short people unless you put the container on a tea table. The gun shape decided that it’s easier to push down form a higher angle.</p>

<p>For model 2, it’s hard to operate the switch button for people who have small hands. Ideally the user should be able to operate the blender with one hand, but with this model, people with small hands may need a second hand to change the switches.</p>

<p>The design of model 3 is in cone-shape which is easy to hold for different hand size. But the problem is that in making this physical prototype, I didn’t control the size well and made it much larger than what I thought. So for people with smaller hand it’s hard to reach the control button.</p>

<p>Here is an one minute clip of the usability testing with these three model prototypes:</p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe src="http://hcid.us//player.vimeo.com/video/84949884" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe> 
</div>


<h1>Reflection</h1>

<p>When designing physical device, it’s easier to think with our hands to see what works. Even holding a simple object can help with designing the shape. And with a little effort, you can try out many different approaches in a second which help me to narrow down my choices rapidly.</p>

<p>I found that Lo-fi 3d prototype provide a more concrete context for interaction designers to think about the interaction with a physical object. And it’s also a good practice to think human computer interaction in a manner of human factors and ergonomics.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Model Prototype Exercise: ecoATM]]></title>
    <link href="http://hcid.us/blog/2014/01/21/model-prototype-exercise-ecoatm/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-21T22:42:27-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://hcid.us/blog/2014/01/21/model-prototype-exercise-ecoatm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="video-container">
<iframe src="http://hcid.us//player.vimeo.com/video/84655899" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe> 
</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paper Prototype Assignment: Wearable UIs]]></title>
    <link href="http://hcid.us/blog/2014/01/21/paper-prototype-assignment-wearable-uis/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-21T17:49:25-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://hcid.us/blog/2014/01/21/paper-prototype-assignment-wearable-uis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Design</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a1/metronome.jpg" width="160">
For this paper prototype assignment, I designed a metronome application that works on both mobile phone and smart watch. It helps to improve musical performance like a traditional metronome while wearable device enabled us to create an even better user experience.</p>

<p>In the picture is a mechanical wind-up metronome which can produce a steady beats: “Da Da Da Da &hellip;”. The consistent tempo help internalizing a clear sense of timing and tempo while musician is playing. By adjusting the metronome, the device can produce varying tempi, usually ranging from 40 to 208 BPM(Beats Per Minutes).</p>

<p>Existing software metronomes and electronic metronomes usually produce the tempo by sound. The problem with using sound is that the sound may be interruptive for audience, and it’s hard to follow the sound on stage(noisy environment).</p>

<p>One thing I found most excited about using Pebble is vibrating on wrist. It enabled a new dimension of sensing information from a digital device without actively paying attention to the device. My idea is by setting the smartwatch to vibrate in a certain tempo, to give musician a more strong sense of the beats.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img class="left" src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a1/sketch.JPG" width="320"></p>

<p>I sketched my first design on whiteboard. It uses the mobile phone interface to set the tempo, while user can also adjust the tempo directly from the watch.</p>

<p>There are two ways to change the BPM value from the phone. One is by spinning the wheel in the middle of the screen, and the other one is by continuously tapping on the button to give an approximate speed. The first method is more accurate and the second one is more intuitive and more useful for composers.
The wheel is easy to understand, it’s like a metaphor of physical tuner. But I’m not sure about the “tapping” part. So I start to make a paper prototype and test this design.</p>

<h2>Prototype</h2>

<p>I build the first version of this prototype within 10 minutes. It’s a quick and dirty one, with only the necessary components on one white paper. To operate this prototype, I need to change the BPM value by writing on a small sticky note and change it while the user using the prototype.</p>

<p>I made a watch face and attach it to a Pebble watch so that the user can actually wear the watch and try the interactions in a more realistic setting. Once the user click start on the phone, the smart watch will launch this app which allow the user to adjust the tempo by the “up/down” button, and exit the app through the “Home” button.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a1/p1.1.jpg" width="320">
<img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a1/p1.2.jpg" width="320"></p>

<p>As some effects can’t be implemented with paper prototype, I will just tell them what happens on the interface or the devices. That includes slight changes on the BPM number, the vibrating of the watch, the sound tempo make by the phone, and the backlight feedback for clicking the tap button.</p>

<p>After several tests, I build a second version based on the feedbacks from the tests with the first paper prototype.</p>

<p>With the second paper prototype, I use cardboard to create a base in the shape of an iPhone so that the user can actually hold the phone on hand. I use a scrolling bar to change the BPM value so that the feedback from tapping and wheel could be faster in the testing. And the scrolling up and down actually simulate the animation I want for this interface. While the user is adjusting the wheel, I will scroll the bar up or down according to the user’s operation. In the first time the user touch the “Tap” button, a pop-up dialog will show up to tell the user how to use this button.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a1/p2.1.JPG" width="320">
<img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/a1/p2.2.jpg" width="320"></p>

<h2>Testing &amp; Analysis</h2>

<p>This is a minute clip presenting the usability testing for the 2 iterations of my paper prototype:</p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe src="http://hcid.us//player.vimeo.com/video/84655291" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe> 
</div>


<p>During the tests with the first prototype, I found that the text “Try tap your tempo” on the left side is extremely helpful for the user to understand how to use it. I tried to remove it and test it with another user, and it failed in the tapping part. The user can’t understand how to use the Tap button without this simple instruction. But I also noticed that this text instruction is unnecessary after the user figure out how to use it. So I change it to a dialog format.</p>

<p>On the other hand, spinning the wheel is more like a self explaining UI component, user can easily figure out how to use it. That may because it looks just like a rotary knob, and it’s natural for it to change the number above it. And this metaphor is widely used in many software interface for turning volume, adjusting parameters and also hardwares such as the classic iPod.</p>

<p>I found that changing the number instantly (or faster) will largely help the user to understand the UI, and replacing the sticky notes is too time-consuming in the test. That’s why I use a scrolling bar for changing the BPM value in the improved version, as it’s just an increasing array of numbers.</p>

<p>Another problem I found in the testing is that user barely use the interface on smartwatch to adjust the tempo. Most of the time they just use the mobile phone to adjust the tempo and to start/stop the beats, although most of them like the idea of vibrating on smartwatch. On a second thought, this app can totally work without the mobile phone: adjusting one number is easy enough to operate on a watch with a simple interface like the one I designed. Moreover if the smartwatch have a motion sensor and microphone, it’s possible to ask the user to set the tempo by snapping their finger which is even more fun to use.</p>

<p>Beside adjusting the tempo, the phone actually allow us to do more complicate operations. For example, the user can choose a song from the music library and let the watch vibrate in a rhythmic beats, or use the phone to connect and sync the tempo among multiple smart watches, which may be useful for a band to collaborate.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paper Prototype Exercise: Coffee Ordering Tablet App]]></title>
    <link href="http://hcid.us/blog/2014/01/21/paper-prototype-exercise-coffee-ordering-tablet-app/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-21T17:49:01-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://hcid.us/blog/2014/01/21/paper-prototype-exercise-coffee-ordering-tablet-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/e1/overview.JPG" width="320"></p>

<p>In the first week of our prototyping class, we explored paper prototyping through a quick exercise: to design a simple coffee ordering tablet app that allowed users to order three different types of coffee in three different sizes.</p>

<p>We have to make a paper prototype of our design very quickly and then test the paper prototype with users and evaluate the design.</p>

<p>We started with sketching out our ideas for the UI independently and then gathered to critique and discuss different approaches. Then we quickly build our first paper prototype, and test it with any people around that are available.</p>

<p>The usability testing and the feedbacks from the users helped us to find some design flaws. After multiple iterations, we made a lot of improvements to our initial design and the final version of our prototype have much better performance in the usability testing.</p>

<p><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/e1/1.jpg" width="160"><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/e1/2.jpg" width="160"><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/e1/3.jpg" width="160"><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/e1/4.jpg" width="160"><img src="http://hcid.us/images/prototyping/e1/5.jpg" width="160"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
